[{"question": "Who invented C Language.?", "option1": "A) Charles Babbage", "option2": "B) Grahambel", "option3": "C) Dennis Ritchie", "option4": "D) Steve Jobs", "ans": "C"}, {"question": "C Language is a successor to which language.?", "option1": "A) FORTRAN", "option2": "B) D Language", "option3": "C) BASIC", "option4": "D) B Language", "ans": "D"}, {"question": "C is a which level language.?", "option1": "A) Low Level", "option2": "B) High Level", "option3": "C) Low + High", "option4": "D) None", "ans": "B"}, {"question": "Low level language is .?", "option1": "A) Human readable like language.", "option2": "B) language with big program size.", "option3": "C) language with small program size.", "option4": "D) Difficult to understand and readability is questionable.", "ans": "D"}, {"question": "High level language is a .?", "option1": "A) Human readable like language.", "option2": "B) language with small program size.", "option3": "C) language with big program size.", "option4": "D) language which is difficult to understand and not human readable.", "ans": "A"}, {"question": "Which program outputs \"Hello World..\" .?", "option1": "A) main()\n{\n  scanf(\"Hello World..\");\n}", "option2": "B) main()\n{\n  printf(\"Hello World..\");\n}", "option3": "C) main()\n{\n  print(\"Hello World..\");\n}", "option4": "D) main()\n{\n  scan(\"Hello World..\");\n}", "ans": "B"}, {"question": "C is _______ type of programming language.?", "option1": "A) Object Oriented", "option2": "B) Procedural", "option3": "C) Bit level language", "option4": "D) Functional", "ans": "B"}, {"question": "What is the present C Language Standard.?", "option1": "A) C99 ISO/IEC 9899:1999", "option2": "B) C11\u00a0ISO/IEC 9899:2011", "option3": "C) C05\u00a0ISO/IEC 9899:2005", "option4": "D) C10\u00a0ISO/IEC 9899:2010", "ans": "B"}, {"question": "What are the new features of C11 or ISO IEC 9899 2011 standard.?", "option1": "A) Type generic Macros, Static Assertions", "option2": "B) Multi Threading, Anonymous Unions, quick_exit", "option3": "C) Bounds Checking Interfaces, Anonymous Strurctures", "option4": "D) All", "ans": "D"}, {"question": " C language was invented in which laboratories.?", "option1": "A) Uniliver Labs", "option2": "B) IBM Labs", "option3": "C) AT&T Bell Labs", "option4": "D) Verizon Labs", "ans": "C"}, {"question": " BCPL Language is also called..?", "option1": "A) C Language", "option2": "B) B Language", "option3": "C) D Language", "option4": "D) None", "ans": "D"}, {"question": " C language was invented to develop which Operating System.?", "option1": "A) Android", "option2": "B) Linux", "option3": "C) Ubuntu", "option4": "D) Unix", "ans": "D"}, {"question": " C language was invented in the year.?", "option1": "A) 1999", "option2": "B) 1978", "option3": "C) 1972", "option4": "D) 1990", "ans": "C"}, {"question": " C language is used in the development of .?", "option1": "A) Databases", "option2": "B) Graphic applications", "option3": "C) Word Processors", "option4": "D) All of the above", "ans": "D"}, {"question": " A C program is a combination of.?", "option1": "A) Statements", "option2": "B) Functions", "option3": "C) Variables", "option4": "D) All of the above", "ans": "D"}]
